I had the craziest dream last night.
I was dancing the White Swan.
It was different choreography, though.
It was more like the Bolshoi's.
It was the prologue,
when Rothbart casts his spell.
Look how pink. So pretty...
Pretty!
- You're in a good mood.
- He promised to feature me more this season.
Well, he certainly should.
You've been there long enough,
and you're the most dedicated
dancer in the company.
Up.
- What's that?
- What?
There.
Nothing.
You're sure you don't want me
to come with you?
You're a sweet girl.
Did you see Beth today?
I can't believe she's back.
- Of course she's back.
- What, she can't take a hint?
The company is broke.
No one comes to see her anymore.
Oh, nobody actually comes
to see ballet full stop.
That's not true. I heard The Royal
had one of their best seasons yet.
He just needs to try something new.
That's all.
No, someone new.
- Like who?
- Like someone who's not approaching menopause.
It's sad.
What's sad?
Beth's such a beautiful dancer.
Yeah, so is my grandmother.
- Well Fonteyn danced into her fifties.
- Yeah, we know.
Great.
Thought I'd fucking missed my stop.
It's a hell-fit all the way from 79th.
Beautiful as always, Nina.
Relax.
And one, and two,
and three, and four.
Stop, John.
One second.
Okay, take position.
And one, and two,
and three, and up.
and three, and four.
Hello, dear.
We all know the story.
Virginal girl, pure and sweet,
trapped in the body of a swan.
She desires freedom
that only true love can break the spell.
Her wish is nearly granted
in the form of a Prince.
But before he can declare his love,
The lustful twin, the Black Swan,
tricks and seduces him.
Devastated,
the White Swan leaps off a cliff,
killing herself.
And in death...
finds freedom.
- Good morning, company.
- Good morning.
We will open our season
with Swan Lake.
Done to death, I know.
But not like this.
We strip it down,
make it visceral and real.
A new production
needs a new Swan Queen.
A fresh face to present to the world.
But... Which of you
can embody both Swans?
The White, and the Black.
All the soloists I tapped:
Go to your scheduled rehearsals
this afternoon.
And the girls I didn't tap:
Meet me in the principals' studio at 5:00.
Thank you.
All right.
- Let's go. Did we do left side?
- Yes, mistress.
Fuck! Fuck!
What?
If I was only casting the White Swan,
she'd be yours.
But I'm not.
Maestro, Odile's coda, please.
Now show me your Black Swan, Nina.
Not so controlled.
Seduce us.
Not just the Prince, but the court,
the audience, the entire world.
Come on,
like a spider spinning a web.
Attack it, attack it!
Come on!
Well...
- Good of you to join us.
- Sorry...
Girls, this is Lily.
Straight off the plane from San Francisco.
She's filling Rebecca's old spot.
- Hey.
- Get warmed up.
No, it's okay.
I'm good.
Should I go again?
No, thanks, Nina.
I've seen enough.
Veronica, the White Swan variation.
Come on, come on, come on, please.
All right, Maestro.
Two, three...
So how'd it go?
You were late, so I called
Susie in the office.
An audition! I can't believe
he just sprang that on you.
So?
It was fine.
Just fine?
Oh, sweetheart...
You tell me about it.
Nina, everything all right?
I'm fine.
Almost done.
You're working yourself too hard.
- We all have off days.
- That girl, um, barged in.
I'm sure she didn't mean to.
For a starter, if I hadn't taken you to each of
your classes, you'd have been completely lost.
I'm going to talk to him tomorrow.
I'm going to tell him I finished it.
You don't need to lie.
You won't convince him
one way or the other.
Oh, sweetheart.
I know it's disappointing.
When you start getting older,
there's all this
ridiculous pressure.
God knows I understand.
But it's all right.
No matter what.
You'll probably get to dance
the part of the cat again.
That's such a wonderful part.
Or maybe he'll make you a big swan.
Either way, you'll shine.
You know...
Everything will be better
in the morning.
It always is.
Sweet girl.
Yes, Nina?
Do you have a minute?
- Now's not a good time. I get it.
- Now is perfect.
So...
I just wanted to tell you that
I practiced the coda last night and
I finished.
I thought you should know.
Okay, Nina, listen. Honestly,
I don't care about your technique.
- You should know that by now.
- Yeah, but yesterday...
No.
Anyway...
I've already chosen Veronica.
Sorry.
Okay, thank you.
That's it?
You're not going to
try and change my mind?
You must have thought
it was possible.
Otherwise, what are you
doing here all dolled up?
I came to ask for the part.
Well...
The truth is...
When I look at you,
all I see is the White Swan.
Yes, you're beautiful,
fearful, fragile.
Ideal casting.
But the Black Swan?
It's a hard fucking job to dance both.
I can dance the Black Swan, too.
Really?
In four years,
every time you dance,
I see obsess getting each and every move
perfectly right, but I never see you lose yourself.
Ever.
All that discipline for what?
- I just want to be perfect.
- You what?
I want to be perfect.
Perfection is not just about control.
It's also about letting go.
Surprise yourself so you can
surprise the audience. Transcendence.
And very few have it in them.
I think I do have it in me.
You bit me?
I can't believe you bit me!
I'm sorry.
Man, that fucking hurt!
What?
Why's she always staring at me?
Hey, it's been posted.
Hey, it's up!
Veronica.
Congratulations.
Hey!
Why would you say that?
Your idea of some sick joke?
What?
Fuck you.
Hey, Nina!
Congratulations!
Congratulations.
You're so beautiful.
- Hello?
- Hi.
What is it?
What's wrong?
I'm fine.
He picked me, Mom.
Do you hear me?
- For Swan Lake?
- I'm going to be Swan Queen!
Mom!
I'll be home soon.
I just wanted to let you know.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
Mom?
Mom, are you in your room?
Nina?
Are you home?
Nina, when you get out
I'm in the kitchen.
Come on, sweetie.
My daughter, the Swan Queen.
It's our favorite.
Vanilla with strawberry filling.
Oh, Mom, not too big.
Oh, that's way, way too much.
- It's a celebration. It's just this once.
- Mom...
My stomach's still in knots.
Fine.
Then it's garbage!
No, Mom, don't.
I'm sorry.
I'm just...
I'm just so proud of you.
It looks so yummy.
Okay, okay.
Thank you.
Thank you, Nina.
That's very nice.
Very nice.
But I knew the White Swan
wouldn't be a problem.
The real work will your
metamorphosis into her evil twin.
And I know I saw
a flash of her yesterday.
So get ready to give me
more of that bite.
Excellent.
That evil force is pulling you that you
can't escape. That's just out of your control.
So you sense it, you get aware of it more:
"It's taking me, it's taking me."
A little bit more desperate.
Right, and you can maybe go up a little bit
and then come down, and then...
That's it.
Watch the way she moves.
Imprecise,
but effortless.
She's not faking it.
Gorgeous!
Okay, that's beautiful.
Let's start again from the beginning.
You'll room with Beth from now on,
so be considerate.
Thanks, Susie.
Those are for you, from Mr. Leroy.
They're beautiful.
I'll be back in a second.
Let me come back to you, please.
Let's go.
Ready to be thrown to the wolves?
We need our cash,
so please don't forget to smile.
Ladies and gentlemen, please,
may I have your attention?
Good evening.
Let me make this
very important announcement.
You all had had the chance and
the privilege to be enchanted, transported,
and even sometimes devastated,
by the performances
of this true artist of our company.
She's been a crucial
inspiration to my work.
A role model to all dancers,
and even more than that,
a deeply appreciated
presence on our stage.
You all know who I am talking about.
Ladies and gentlemen, Beth Macintyre.
But as we all know,
every great career
has to come to an end.
Beth is retiring at the end of season.
She will be giving her
farewell performance as Melpomene,
the role she originated
in my first ballet.
My little princess,
we honor you.
You will be greatly missed,
and never forgotten.
But as we bid adieu to one star,
we welcome another.
We're opening our season
with my new version of Swan Lake.
Taking the role of our new Swan Queen,
the exquisite Nina Sayers.
You'll soon have the pleasure
of seeing her perform,
but right now, let's please raise a glass:
To all of us. To Beth. To Nina.
To beauty.
Just a second.
Just a second!
Come on!
I'm about to burst!
Hey, it's you!
I don't think we ever
officially met.
- I'm Lily.
- Hi, I'm Nina.
Yes, our new Swan Queen.
- Here, hold this.
- Yeah, sure.
You must be so excited.
Are you freaking out?
- Yeah...
- Yeah?
Oh, it's okay.
Oh, I'd be losing my mind.
I should get back...
No, no, no, come on, stay.
Keep me company.
Excuse me.
Oh, there you are.
Come on.
Hey. They tried to eat you alive,
but here you are.
You did well.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
Where are you going?
Upper west side.
Stop at my place for a drink.
It's on the way.
Thomas, you need to say hello
to Karen Holloway.
A minute more of ass-kissing.
I'll be back. Wait for me here, all right?
Hello, Karen!
Beth!
I'm so sorry to hear
you're leaving the company.
What did you do to get this role?
He always said you were
such a frigid little girl.
What did you do to make
him change his mind?
Did you suck his cock?
Not all of us have to.
You fucking whore!
You're a fucking little whore!
Whoa, what's going on here?
Hey, I need to talk to you.
- You're drunk. You should go home.
- I need to talk to you.
No! Don't you do that!
Don't you dismiss me like that!
My little princess, please.
Pull it together.
- Come.
- I'm coming by later.
I have something for you.
It's a token of my appreciation.
- Right.
- You make the most of it, Nina.
Don't worry. It's typical.
Please. I thought it'd be good
to talk about the role.
Drown this a little.
I don't want there to be
any boundaries between us.
- No, me neither.
- Good.
So...
You got a boyfriend?
No.
Have you had many in the past?
A few.
But no one serious.
You're not a virgin are you?
No.
So there's nothing
to be embarrassed about.
And you enjoy making love?
Excuse me?
Come on, sex.
Do you enjoy it?
We need to be able
to talk about this.
I've got a little homework
assignment for you.
Go home and touch yourself.
Live a little.
Well it's late.
Lots of work tomorrow.
The doorman will
find a cab for you.
Sounds like quite an evening.
I wish I could have been there.
You know I asked.
I know you did.
Susie told me.
Guess he wanted you
all to himself.
But why?
Don't blame him.
Where'd you get these?
They're fake.
Fooled me.
I can do it.
He must have been
by your side all night.
Showing you off.
- Oh, Nina...
- It's just a rash.
Rash?
What are you talking about?
It was worse a few days ago.
It's fine already.
- You've been scratching yourself again.
- No I haven't.
Mom!
This disgusting habit...
Jesus Christ, I thought
you were done with this, Nina.
Shrugs.
You'll keep wearing the shrugs.
Sit down.
You have the white one,
and the pink one.
And that'll hide it.
And then I'll dig out that expensive
coverup. We still have some.
No one will see it.
Mom, please,
It's the role, isn't it?
It's all this pressure.
I knew it'd be too much.
I knew it.
You're all right.
You'll be all right.
Beth's in the hospital.
She had an accident.
Oh no!
Beth?
What happened?
She walked into the street
and got hit by a car.
You know what?
I'm almost sure
she did it on purpose.
How do you know?
Because everything Beth does comes
from within, from some dark impulse.
I guess that's what makes her
so thrilling to watch.
So dangerous.
Even perfect at times.
But also so damned destructive.
Was it right after we saw her?
Wait, wait, wait.
This has nothing to do with you.
It's not your problem,
so don't let yourself be distracted.
This is your moment, Nina.
Don't let it go.
What are you doing?
Nina?
Sweetie, are you ready for me?
And...
Come on!
Forget about control, Nina.
I want to see passion.
Come on.
Stiff like a dead corpse.
Let it go.
And again.
Feels like you have your diaphragm
is in a bit of a contraction?
I'm okay.
Breathe in to this hand.
Breathe in, all the way.
Good.
And exhale.
Does it feel jammed in the front
every time you plie?
Sometimes, not always.
- One more pull, okay?
- Okay.
- Is that okay?
- Yeah.
David,
can I ask you a question?
Honestly,
would you fuck that girl?
No.
No one would.
Nina...
Your dancing is just as frigid...
Fuck!
We're still working here, please.
Lights!
The lights!
Thank you!
Okay, guys, you can go.
Thanks for your patience.
No, no, you stay.
You stay.
Have fun, you two.
Okay.
Come here.
Come, come, come, come.
I'll be the Prince.
Let it go. Let it go.
Feel my touch.
Respond to it.
Come on.
Open your mouth.
Open it. Open up.
That was me seducing you,
when it needs to be
the other way around.
Please...
Who is that?
Hey.
You okay?
You can't smoke in here.
Well, I won't tell if you won't.
So...
The big day's getting closer
and closer, huh?
Well, I can't wait.
I think you're going to be amazing.
Thanks.
So...
Do  you want to talk about it?
It's that hard to.
Leroy playing
a little too rough for you?
Come on, Nina.
He's a prick.
He's brilliant.
Sure, but it's not like
he's all warm and fuzzy.
What you don't know is...
Someone's hot for teacher!
Oh, come on, it's okay.
I don't blame you.
I should go home.
Nina, come on.
I'm just playing around.
Nina!
Sweetie?
What are you doing in there?
Again.
Do you have any corrections?