(male narrator) Previously
on Battlestar Galactica.
Now you're telling me
you're a machine.
The robot.
You knew I wanted access
to the defense mainframe.
Do you have any idea what they
will do to me if they find out?
Get down.
(Adama) Moments ago,
this ship received word...
of a Cylon attack against
our home worlds is underway.
As of this moment,
we are at war.
All right,
we can take three more people.
Giving up my seat.
I've decided you're an expression
of my subconscious mind...
playing itself out
during my waking states.
So I'm only in your head?
No.
There maybe Cylon agents
living among us.
Some may not even know
they're Cylons at all.
They could be
sleeper agents...
programmed to perfectly impersonate
human beings until activation.
[clock ticking]
[ticking echoing]
[controls beeping]
And one minute to mark.
[timer beeping]
[woman chattering]
[people chattering]
God has a plan for you, Gaius. He has
a plan for everything and everyone.
Gaius?
Are you even listening to me?
(man on P.A.) Passengers,
30 seconds to mark.
(Roslin)
Planet. Men. Women. Age.
You know what? Do this after the
jump. It's all right. Go ahead.
[sighs]
[clock ticking]
[sniffles]
You have to
believe in something.
I believe in a world
that I can and do understand.
A rational universe explained
through rational means.
[snickers]
I love you.
That's not rational.
I know.
No, but you're not rational.
You're also not really here.
Neither am I.
(pilot) Madam President,
ladies and gentlemen...
our 33 minutes
are almost up once again.
Please prepare for our
faster-than-light jump. Thank you.
Cutting it a little close
this time, aren't we, Billy?
Pilot says they've had to
reboot the FTL computer again.
(Cally) Why do the Cylons
come every 33 minutes?
Why isn't it 34, 35...
(Tyrol)
Cally.
What?
Shut up.
15 seconds.
Sir, jump 237 underway.
53 ships have jumped.
10 still reporting trouble
with their FTL drives...
including Colonial One.
We're getting slower.
[timer beeping]
Maybe this time.
[timers bleeping]
[alarm ringing]
(Gaeta)
Dradis contact.
It's the Cylons.
Damn it.
Not this time, maybe the next.
[alarms buzzing]
I got another idea
for the next cycle.
(pilot)
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm afraid the Cylons
have appeared again.
However, our FTL drive is now
working and we will jump momentarily.
Five days now.
There are limits...
to the human body,
the human mind.
Tolerances
that you can't push beyond.
Those are facts...
provable facts.
Everyone has their limit.
All right, you know the drill,
people. Scatter formation.
(Apollo)
Keep them off the civies
and don't stray
beyond the recovery line.
Watch the ammo hoists
for the main guns.
You've got a red light
right there.
[explosions]
[electricity surging]
[alarm beeping]
We have a hit
on the starboard bow.
Away
the damage control parties.
Basestar is launching raiders.
[people chattering]
[spaceships humming]
Colonial One is ready to jump.
All civilian ships away,
including Colonial One.
Recover fighters.
Stand by to jump.
Combat landings.
All fighters aboard, sir.
Execute jump.
[woman chattering on radio]
[bleeps]
Jump 237 complete.
All civilian ships present
and accounted for, sir.
Start the clock.
And let's start prepping
for the next jump.
Clock is running. 33 minutes.
Mark.
You got 32 minutes, people.
[moans]
You know you're not safe.
No, of course not.
The Cylons
will follow us again...
as they have
the last 237 times.
You're right, you know.
There are limits.
Eventually,
you'll make a mistake.
And then you'll kill us all.
Yes.
Yes, I know.
But not for
another 33 minutes.
[clock ticking]
[people chattering]
(Adama) I want to try
something new this time.
Divide the fleet
into six groups.
Then they jump...
[Adama sighs]
Then they jump two more times and on
the fourth jump, we rendezvous at...
a common set of coordinates.
24 jumps to plot,
we're breaking our humps...
calculating one jump
every 33 minutes.
Get off my jacket.
Are you eating this?
Not anymore.
(Apollo) Combat landings expected
again to be the order of the day...
so double-check
your undercarriage before...
Look, you've all done this
237 times.
You know what to do.
No mistakes.
And let's make it to 238.
And good luck
and be careful out there.
[pilots chattering]
Can you do me a favor? Tell
Capt. Apollo he owes me one wing.
(Dave)
You got it, Chief.
No, Cally, there's three.
I know there's three.
Can you check it again
for me, please?
Yeah.
At least get some of them
starting to work.
We'll sleep when we're dead.
Come on.
Boomer.
Heard the latest? They say
Cylons look like us now.
[keys clicking]
Primary fuel?
Primary fuel 2893 KRG.
Marine told one of the pilots that
we marooned some guy back on Ragnar...
because they actually thought
that he was a Cylon.
You know what?
I don't give a frak.
Red light on
the number four thruster.
Go make a visual ID.
See if it's blocked.
Right.
A little rough on your
new ECO, don't you think?
He's not my ECO.
He's some refugee from Triton that I've
been saddled with and I didn't ask you.
Helo's gone, Sharon.
I didn't ask you that, either.
Sorry.
Colony?
Saggitaron.
How many have you got?
5,251 survivors
from Saggitaron, last count.
We can't transmit photos yet. If you
want, you can leave them with us...
or you can put them
on the board outside.
Sorry.
Thanks.
Next.
Colony?
Update on the headcount,
Madam President.
How did we lose 300?
There were some overcounts...
a few deaths from wounds and a
few missing during the last attack.
Do you want children, Gaius?
Let me think about that
for a minute.
No.
Procreation
is one of God's commandments.
Really?
I'm sure someday, if you're a
good Cylon, he'll reward you...
with a lovely little walking
toaster of your very own.
I want us
to have a child, Gaius.
You can't be serious.
It's Dr. Amarak.
What was that?
I'm so sorry for interrupting
you while you were speaking.
You were just saying?
[mutters]
I was just saying
that a Dr. Amarak...
had requested
to speak with the President.
Dr. Amarak. I see.
You know him?
Have you always been able
to multitask like this?
Yes. Yes.
I used to work with him
at the Ministry of Defense.
It says here that he's uncovered
important information...
regarding how the Cylons were
able to defeat colonial defenses.
I was always a little worried
he was on to us.
Were you going
to speak to him?
Perhaps I should speak to him
if you're busy.
Actually, I think he wanted to
speak directly with the President.
It sounded urgent.
It must be very important.
Maybe something about a certain
traitor in the President's inner circle?
There's not enough time
before we jump.
I want him on board first
thing during the next cycle.
Thank you, Doctor.
I'd say you have
a serious problem.
If I can help.
He's a strange one, isn't he?
[rain pattering]
[panting]
[grunts]
[remote beeps]
[Cylon whirring]
[metal scrapping]
[shouting]
[sighs]
(pilot)
Landing Bay, Team Alpha...
Did you see it?
Twelve more cases of nervous
exhaustion. That makes 61.
Have the docs start pumpin'
them up with stimulants...
and get them back on the line.
Pilots, too.
Fuel report.
One out of every three,
every other cycle.
That's going to come back
and bite us in the ass.
We have too much work and
not enough people to do it.
(Dualla)
Fuel report.
I've already signed
one of these.
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
Comm traffic two
from the President.
Is this my 10 minutes
or this yours?
Yours. I took 10 last time.
I'll see you guys in combat.
I believe
it was your 10 minutes.
If the old man's so tired he
can't remember, then it's his turn.
[people chattering]
You see the note
from the XO?
Yeah, I saw it. No way.
(Apollo)
Kara, everyone else...
- I don't fly with stims.
They blunt your reflexes,
your reaction time.
Come on, Kara,
give me a break. Just...
Why are we arguing
about this?
I have no idea.
Neither do I.
You're the CAG, act like one.
What the hell does that mean?
It means that you're still acting
like you're everyone's best friend.
We're not friends,
you're the CAG.
"Be careful out there"?
Our job isn't to be careful, it's to
shoot Cylons out of the frakking sky.
"Good hunting"
is what you say.
And now, one of your idiot
pilots is acting like a child...
and refusing to take her pills.
So she either says, "Yes, sir"...
and obeys a direct order or
you smack her in the mouth...
and you drag her sorry ass down to
sickbay and you make her take those pills.
[snickers]
Well, I'm glad
I'm not working for you.
You're damn right you're glad.
So, do I have to smack you
in the mouth, Lieutenant?
No, sir. I'll take my pills.
Perfect.
[clears throat]
Carry on.
Yes, sir.
(man on P.A.) Pilots to ready
room for pre-flight briefing.
Pilots to ready room.
What?
[groans]
Jump 238 complete.
Start the clock.
33 minutes.
Mark.
All civilian ships
present and...
[indicator bleeping]
Strike my last.
One civilian ship missing
and unaccounted for, sir.
Which one?
The Olympic Carrier.
Commercial passenger vessel.
Were they left behind?
I think I accounted for all
civilian ships before we left.
You think?
Did you or didn't you?
They're not logged in, sir. I think
they may have been left behind.
How many people aboard ship?
1,345 souls, sir.
You're telling me we left over 1,300
people to die at the hands of the Cylons?
It may not have been
her fault, sir.
It may have simply been
a navigational error...
and they jumped
to the wrong coordinates...
or the Cylons destroyed the
ship before they jumped...
Or 50 other things
may have happened.
The point is we don't know
what the hell did happen.
Yes, we're tired.
Yes, there's no relief.
Yes, the Cylons keep coming after
us time after time after time...
and yes, we are still expected
to do our jobs.
We make mistakes, people die.
There aren't many of us left.
Carry on.
Okay. Next crisis?
[sighs]
List of calls?
Yes.
But first, where's the doctor
that's supposed to be on board?
What's his name?
Dr. Amarak.
Yes.
Oh.
He was on the Olympic Carrier.
[seagulls cawing]
God is watching out for you,
Gaius.
[birds chirping]
The universe is a vast
and complex system.
Coincidental,
serendipitous events...
are bound to occur. Indeed
they are to be expected.
It's part of the pattern,
part of the plan.
Dr. Amarak
posed a threat to you.
Now he's gone. Logic says
there's a connection.
A connection, maybe.
But not God.
There is no God or gods,
singular or plural.
There are no large invisible
men, or women for that matter...
in the sky taking a personal interest
in the fortunes of Gaius Baltar.
Be careful.
That which God gives,
he can also take away.
15 seconds.
[timer beeping]
Maybe this time.
Dradis?
No enemy contacts.
Keep the clock running.
What do you think?
I think we wait.
[beeping]
[sighs]
Get me the President.
Why this time?
Was it something that you did?
We had a new plan, but we didn't
have time to implement it yet.
We lost that ship during the
last cycle, the Olympic Carrier.
Does that have something
to do with it?
(Adama)
Possibly.
Are you there?
Yeah, I'm here.
What do we do now, Commander? I've
got people on the verge over here.
We're going to go to Condition Two. We
have to take advantage of this time...
and let our people
get some rest.
All right.
And how long do we stay
at Condition Two?
Until I'm satisfied
they're not going to return.
It's a military decision.
It is. I know that.
You're right and I defer to
your decision. And, Commander...
let your men and women...
know how grateful I am for the
job that they are doing, please.
Thank them for me.
Thank you, Madam President.
Thank you.
Contact Apollo.
Tell him to set up a combat
patrol around the fleet...
and order his other pilots
to land immediately.
All right, people,
you heard the order.
Boomer, Starbuck, form up with
me. We'll fly the first CAP.
I want everyone else back on
Galactica and in their racks.
Three-hour rotation.
(Starbuck)
Hey, Apollo...
not that I'm not honored by being
chosen to sit in my cockpit...
for the next three hours but...
But why you?
Take a guess.
Because I'm on drugs?
You got it. This patrol
is 100% stimulated.
[Starbuck laughing]
(Crashdown)
Anyone else feels like...
they have frakking ants
crawling behind their eyeballs?
(Apollo)
How about you, Boomer?
Doc tells me you're holding up
better than anybody in the squadron.
(Boomer)
I'm tired like everybody else.
You never seem it.
(Starbuck)
That's 'cause she's a Cylon.
You're going to make me come
over there and kick your ass.
Okay. Let's set up
a patrol here...
before somebody gets hurt.
Follow me.
(Starbuck)
Copy that, Apollo.
A couple hours rack time
does sound awfully sweet...
right about now.
You deserve it.
You know, the truth is...
all this has me feeling more
alive than I have in years.
You look that way, too.
It's good to see you
without the cup in your hand.
Don't start.
I know there's a whole lot
of people aboard this ship...
that wish you weren't feeling
as good as you are.
If the crew doesn't hate the
XO, then he's not doin' his job.
Besides, got to make
the old man look good.
I always look good.
Did you look in a mirror?
Seriously...
Sir.
...it's one thing to push the
crew, it's another to break them.
(Gaeta)
Dradis contact.
Bearing 348,
carom 120, one ship.
Getting recognition signal.
(computer) Initiating response
flash mode. Alpha, alpha.
It's the Olympic Carrier, sir.
Is that confirmed?
It's confirmed, sir.
Thank the gods.
[people chattering]
Action stations.
Put the fleet
into Condition One.
I want all Vipers manned and
ready, but keep them in the tubes.
Mr. Gaeta.
Sir?
Restart the clock. 33 minutes.
[alarms blaring]
I hope you're wrong.
So do I.
(Gaeta)
Clock is running.
So do I.
No. It's all wrong.
If they were left behind, why
didn't the Cylons destroy them?
And why are they
showing up now?
It's God's punishment
for your lack of faith.
That's just great, that is.
A more logical and useful
explanation, please.
All right.
The Olympic Carrier has been
infiltrated by Cylon agents.
They've been
tracking the ship all along.
No.
Then that means...
Logically, in order
for you to survive...
the Olympic Carrier
should be destroyed.
(Boomer) Olympic Carrier,
Olympic Carrier...
this is Raptor 478, call sign
Boomer. I have you in visual contact.
Please respond
on this channel. Over.
(man on radio)
Raptor 478,
this is the Olympic Carrier.
We have you in visual contact.
Thank the Lords of Kobol. You don't
know how relieved we are to see you.
Roger that, Olympic Carrier.
Can I ask about your whereabouts?
We had trouble
with our FTL drive.
Took us almost three hours
to fix.
Have Boomer ask them
how they escaped the Cylons.
Olympic Carrier, Boomer.
I've been directed to ask how
you escaped from the Cylons.
You got me. They were
closing in on us...
when the rest of you
were jumping.
I thought we were goners,
then they just broke off.
Someone must've been
watching out for us.
Roger that.
One other thing, Boomer.
I've got a Dr. Amarak
on board...
who has an urgent matter
to discuss with the President.
He's been driving me crazy.
Olympic Carrier,
can you be more specific?
I'm afraid I can't. He says he knows
something about a traitor in our midst...
and he's unwilling to share
any more than that.
Madam President,
I strongly recommend...
that we cut off all wireless
communication with that ship right away.
[stuttering]
Why?
Look, forgive me for being
rude, but wake up, all right?
The only reason the Olympic
Carrier is still flying...
is because the Cylons
let them survive.
They've been
tracking that ship all along.
There's probably a Cylon
agent aboard right now!
Calm down.
Start over.
Please, Madam President,
I implore you. Listen to me.
Cut off radio communication
with that ship...
before they send via broadcast
signal another computer virus...
to infect our ship shortly
before they blow us all up.
Com. Adama,
are you on the line?
Cut off the speakers.
Put it through the line.
Yes, Madam President. And I'm
inclined to agree with Dr. Baltar.
Good. So do I.
Thank the gods you're with us.
God's got nothing
to do with this.
Boomer, Galactica.
Your orders are to jam all
transmissions from the Olympic Carrier.
No further voice contact
is authorized.
Roger that, Galactica.
(Dualla)
Boomer, Galactica.
Orders are
to send the Olympic Carrier...
the following message
by signal light.
Message begins,
"Maintain present position.
"Do not, repeat, do not approach
the fleet until further notice. "
Message ends.
I'm getting a bad feeling
about where this is headed.
So am I.
If the ship poses a threat to us,
we have to eliminate that threat.
I don't think
they got the message, Apollo.
Yeah, I see it. Boomer, break
wireless silence on my authority.
Warn them to stop their
engines immediately.
I suggest that we evacuate the
passengers and destroy the ship.
It solves the problem
if they're tracking the ship.
What if they're tracking
one of the passengers?
(Boomer) Olympic Carrier,
Olympic Carrier...
you are ordered to stop your
engines immediately. Acknowledge.
Apollo,
they're not responding.
(Apollo) Are you using the same channel?
Yeah, but suddenly
nobody's home.
Starbuck, fire a burst
across their bow.
Copy that.
[snickers]
Boomer, let Galactica know
we have a problem out here.
Commander,
message from Boomer.
The Olympic Carrier is heading
directly for us, sir.
They're refusing all orders
to stop.
[beeping]
(Boomer) Galactica, they're
still not responding...
and continue to head toward
the fleet. Request instructions.
Order the fleet
to execute Jump 240.
Get us between that ship
and the fleet.
Commander! Dradis contact. Strike
that, multiple Dradis contacts.
It's the Cylons.
[alarms blaring]
(Crashdown) The Cylons
are on an intercept course.
They'll be in weapons range
within two minutes.
[alarm sounds]
Radiological alarm!
From where?
The Olympic Carrier, sir.
They've got nukes on board.
Madam President, we have to eliminate
the Olympic Carrier immediately.
There are 1,300 people
on that ship.
(Adama)
We don't know that.
The Cylons may have
captured them already.
She's not going to do it.
She has to do it.
It's not her decision, Gaius.
No?
It's God's choice.
He wants you to repent.
Look, at this point there's no
choice. It's either them or us.
Repent of your sins.
Accept his true love
and you will be saved.
I repent. There, I repent.
I repent.
Do it.
(Boomer)
We have new orders.
We're directed to destroy
the Olympic Carrier...
and return to Galactica.
It's a civilian ship.
(Apollo) Yeah, a
civilian ship with nukes.
I don't see anybody in there,
do you?
The Cylons will be here
any second.
If we're going to do this,
let's just do it.
Starbuck, form up with me.
We'll make one pass
from astern.
(Starbuck)
Lee, what if you're wrong?
Lee, come on.
Lee...
Okay, fire on my mark.
No frakking way, Lee.
Lee? Come on!
[beeping]
Mark.
[rain pattering]
[sighs]
Are you alive?
[panting]
Agathon, Karl C.
Lieutenant, junior grade,
Colonial Fleet.
PK-789-9348.
I know who you are, Helo.
It's all right. I'm a friend.
[guns firing]
[groans]
[gags]
Sharon?
What are you doing here?
Can you walk?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, I think so.
[grunts]
What are you doing here,
I thought...
Let's move, mister.
Sir.
Son.
I gave the order.
It was my responsibility.
I pulled the trigger.
That's mine.
(Billy)
Madam President?
I'm sorry,
you were saying something?
Twenty-four hours, no Cylons.
At least you know
it was the right choice.
The right choice.
I'm sorry, Billy. I think I'd
like some time alone, please.
Of course.
What is it?
Update on the headcount.
Subtract how many?
Actually, you can add one.
A baby was born this morning
on the Rising Star.
A boy.
A baby.
Yeah.
Thank you.