Lily told me that
she saw you crying.
That you were very upset
and that I should
take it easy on you.
I didn't tell her that.
Maybe you need a little break.
A day or two. Or maybe a month.
What do you think?
She shouldn't have said anything.
No, you shouldn't be
whining in the first place.
I didn't.
You could be brilliant.
But you're a coward.
Sorry.
No, stop saying that!
That's exactly what I'm talking about.
Stop being so fucking weak.
Again!
Lily...
Oh, look who's decided
to grace us with her presence.
I need to talk to you.
Okay.
Now.
Shut up.
Come on.
What's up?
You told Thomas about last night?
Oh, yeah. I ran into him in the morning and
he said you guys were having some trouble.
Why would he talk to you?
Oh, excuse me, your highness.
I just told him you're working your ass off
and I think you'll be great.
Well you shouldn't have.
Okay.
Has he tried anything with you?
He has a reputation.
I have a right to be concerned, Nina.
You've been staying late so many nights.
Rehearsing. I just hope
he isn't taking advantage, that's all.
He's not.
Good.
I just don't want you to make
the same mistake I did.
Thanks.
Not like that.
I just mean as far as
my career was concerned.
What career?
The one I gave up to have you.
I'm twenty-eight.
So?
Only that...
Only what?
Nothing.
- What?
- Nothing.
How is your skin?
Fine.
- Are you leaving it alone?
- Mm-hmm.
Let me see.
- Take off your shirt.
- No.
Can I help you?
Who was that?
It was no one.
Hello?
What are you doing here?
I just came by to apologize.
You're right. I should have never
spoken to him about you.
- Sweetheart.
- Give me a second.
- Your dinner...
- Mom, please.
Oh, she's a trip.
How do you know where I live?
I have my ways.
Jesus, relax.
I got it from Susie in the office.
Look, I feel really shitty about what I did,
and I really want to make it up to you.
So how about I take you out to dinner?
- I don't think...
- Okay, that's fine.
What about drinks?
Sweetie, you need to rest.
- Jesus.
- Wait.
What are you doing?
I'm going out.
What?
Nina!
You're on the stage tomorrow.
I can't believe he calls her that.
- It's so gross.
- I think it's sweet.
Little Princess?
- He probably calls every girl that.
- No way.
That's just for Beth.
Well, I bet he'll be calling you
Little Princess any day now.
I don't know about that.
Oh, sure he will.
Just got to let him lick your pussy.
Cheeseburger, extra bloody.
Mmm, dankeschön.
Let me know
if that's juicy enough for you.
Oh, I will.
You have enough cheese?
No, but you do.
Enjoy.
All right.
Wanna spruce up?
What, I carry a spare
in case I wake up
somewhere unexpected.
So how is he?
Thomas.
I wouldn't know.
- Oh, come on.
- I really don't want to talk about that.
Okay.
You really need to relax.
One for you,
one for me.
Oh, and don't worry. It's pure, I promise.
I brought it with me straight from San Francisco.
What is it?
Are you kidding?
You've never rolled?
Oh, relax. Here.
It'll loosen you up.
Wait till you see the night sky.
How long does it last?
A couple hours, tops.
It's okay.
Okay.
Nina, hi!
I thought we could use some company.
So this is Tom and this is Jerry.
- Actually it's Andrew.
- Tom.
- I have to go...
- Oh, no you can't go. I just got us some drinks.
I shouldn't...
We're on the stage tomorrow.
So what are you going to do?
Go home to Mommy?
Come on, live a little.
It's just a couple hours, right?
Tops.
Cheers.
You haven't told me who you are.
I'm a dancer.
No, I mean your name.
- Oh. Nina.
- So are you two sisters?
- Yes.
- No.
- Blood sisters.
- We dance in the same company.
Ah, ballerinas.
No wonder you two look alike.
I see now.
Tom and Jerry here are gay lovers.
- Very funny.
- I like to amuse myself.
I've never been to the ballet.
Then you are definitely not gay.
I mean, it's kind of boring,
isn't it?
- Be honest.
- No it's not.
You know what?
It's just not for everyone.
You should come sometime.
I can comp you tickets whenever you want.
Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah, that would be neat. Thanks.
- Okay well...
I think it's time for another round.
Bottoms up.
So what are you guys
working on now?
Sorry.
Swan Lake.
Yeah?
You know it?
No, not really.
Heard of it.
What's it about?
It's about a girl who gets
turned into a swan,
and she needs love
to break the spell.
But her prince falls for the wrong girl,
and so she kills herself.
It's not a happy ending then.
It's beautiful, actually.
Like you.
Huh?
I said you're beautiful.
That's funny?
Looks like someone might be rolling.
All right, come on.
Come on, it's time to go dance.
Nina!
Hey, what the fuck?
Where you going?
Nina!
Where are you going?
Do you have any idea
what time it is?
Late?
Where have you been?
To the moon and back.
- You've been drinking.
- Ding ding ding ding ding!
- What else?
- Hmm?
What else have you been doing?
Oh, you want to know their names?
- You need to sleep this off.
- There were two. Tom and Jerry.
- Be quiet, Nina.
- And I fucked them both.
Shut your mouth!
- Don't come in here.
- What's this?
It's called privacy.
I'm not twelve anymore.
- You're not my Nina right now...
- Leave me alone!
Sweat girl.
Why didn't you wake me up?
I'm moving out.
My music!
Thomas, I am so sorry.
Keep on going.
Go get warmed up.
That was good.
Actually, really good.
Okay, let's take ten.
Look, he just wanted to mark it
and asked me to step up, okay?
I overslept.
Oops. But hey, at least
you had a good time, right?
You put something in my drink.
Yeah.
And then you just
took off in the morning.
In the morning?
Yeah, you slept over.
Um, no.
Unless your name's Tom
and you had a dick.
What, Nina?
Did you have some sort of
lesbian wet dream about me?
- Stop.
- Oh my God!
Oh my God, you did!
You fantasized about me!
- Shut up!
- Was I good?
The final act.
You're trying to dance.
You've tasted your dream!
Touched it!
Only to have it crushed!
Your heart is broken,
wounded.
Your life force fading.
The blood drips.
The Black Swan stole your love.
There is only one way to end the pain.
You are not fearful,
but filled with acceptance.
And you look down at Rothbart,
and then at the Prince,
and then, yes,
at the audience.
And then you jump.
Go ahead. Jump.
Jump!
Okay, everybody get a drink of water,
then it's notes.
You lost weight.
Take off your shrug, please.
Very good.
Face front.
We're almost done.
And that's it.
Okay.
We're done.
Thank you very much.
Georgina, I'm Lily.
Thomas sent me...
Yes, we have to get you measured
for the Swan Queen costumes.
What's she doing here?
He made me your alternate.
Look, it's just in case.
Thomas.
- Thomas.
- Yes?
It can't be her.
Okay, why don't you just go.
I'll catch up later.
What's going on?
Lily...
You made her my alternate?
There's always an alternate.
Lily is the best choice.
No, she wants my role.
Every dancer in the world
wants your role.
No, this is different.
She is after me.
- She is trying to replace me.
- Nobody is after you.
- No, please believe me...
I know it's been a struggle.
But you just had a breakthrough this morning.
Tomorrow is yours. Just give a great performance
and you won't have to worry about Lily or anybody else.
Now go home and rest.
From the vision again.
What happened?
I've got a life.don't work too hard.
It's a big day tomorrow.
I'm still working in here.
Could you please
turn the lights back on?
Hello?
What are you doing here?
I'm so sorry.
I know how it feels now.
She's trying to replace me.
What do I do?
You stole my things?
I was just trying to be perfect, like you.
Perfect?
I'm not perfect.
I'm nothing.
Nothing!
Nothing, nothing!
Sweet girl.
Mommy?
Stop!
What are you doing?
Sweetie?
Nina?
Nina!
Go away!
Open the door!
Open the door, Nina!
Nina!
Get out!
- What's wrong with you?
- Get out!
- What do you see?
Get out!
It's okay.
I'm here.
You were scratching all night.
Where's my clock?
- Don't worry about that.
- What time is it?
- The show is tonight, I have to...
- No, no, no, no.
Don't worry.
I called the theater and I told them
you aren't feeling well.
I have to go!
- No. No, you don't.
- Let go of me.
You're staying in here
until you feel better.
Where is it?
This role is destroying you.
- Move. Move!
- Nina...!
- What happened to my sweet girl?
- She's gone!
Nina!
Oh, Nina!
No, please!
- You're not well!
- Let go of me!
You can't handle this.
I can't?
I'm the Swan Queen.
You're the one who never left the corps.
Nina!
What are you doing here?
Nina?
She was supposed to be sick.
Give us a minute.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Nina.
What?
I've already asked Lily.
Have you announced it?
After Beth, do you really need
another controversy?
I'm here, Thomas.
I'm doing it.
The only person
standing in your way is you.
It's time to let it go.
Lose yourself.
White Swan, up in ten.
What are you doing?
You need to be upstage.
You suck.
Okay, Nina.
What the fuck?
- Are you okay?
- Nina, are you okay?
Can you tell me
what the fuck happened?
- It wasn't my fault. He dropped me.
- This is a fucking disaster.
Rough start, huh?
Must have been pretty humiliating.
Get out of my room.
I'm worried about the next act.
I'm just not sure you're feeling up to it.
Stop.
Please stop.
How about I dance the Black Swan for you?
Leave me alone!
My turn!
It's my turn!
Black Swan, places in five.
Come on.
Good job.
Fifteen to the last act.
Hey.
You were amazing.
Seriously, I know that things got
a little messed up between us,
but I mean, holy shit,
you completely blew me away!
Okay, well I guess that's it.
So I'll let you finish.
Bye.
Can you hear them?
They love you!
My little princess,
I always knew you had it in you.
Come on.
Let's take you out.
Go get some help.
Go get some help!
What did you do?
- I felt it.
- What?
I felt perfect.
I was perfect.
Nina! Nina! Nina!